\documentclass % Document class (adjust as needed)
% Packages
\usepackage % Packages for advanced mathematicians
\usepackage % Packages for mathematical symbols
\usepackage % Allows arithmetic calculations within the document
\usepackage % Draws cancellation lines to highlight simplified terms
\usepackage[utf8] % Enables UTF-8 encoding for Portuguese characters
\usepackage[portuguese] % Enables Portuguese language support
\usepackage % Use Latin Modern fonts (recommended for Portuguese)
\begin % Body of the document (equation and explanations)
\title % Document title
\author % Name
\date % Date of document
\maketitle % Displays title, author and date
\textbf$, determine the value of $y$ such that: }
\[ ... \]
y = \frac
\begin ... \end
% Sets the width of the first column (50% of the total width)
f\left( x\right) = \frac
\hfill % Space between columns
\begin ... \end
% Sets the width of the second column (50% width)
\begin
y = \frac
Checking if the calculation is correct...
\[ ... \]
\textbf
f\left(-x \right) = \frac
\Rightarrow f\left( -x \right) = \frac
Checking whether the calculation is correct...
\[ ... \]
\text
y = \frac
\Rightarrow y = \frac - \frac}}} \bullet \frac}} }
\Rightarrow y = \frac - \left(x + 1 \right)^}}
\[... \]
\[ y = \frac - -2x +1 \right) - \left( x^ + 2x + 1 \right)} - 1}}
\Rightarrow y = \frac - 2x + 1 - x^ - 2x - 1} - 1} \bullet \frac \]
Checking the code...
\[ \Rightarrow y = \frac - x^ - 2x - 2x + 1 - 1} - 1} \bullet \frac
\Rightarrow y = \frac} - \cancel} - 2x - 2x + \cancel - \cancel} - 1} \bullet \frac \]
\[ y = \frac - 1 \right)}
y = \frac - 1 \right)} \]
\[ \Rightarrow y = \frac \right)}
\Rightarrow y = \frac} \]